Guide to the John Hollander Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
John Hollander papers
1949-2006
YCAL MSS 837
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
18.3
(22 boxes)
Hollander, John, 1929-2013
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of John Hollander, 1966 and 2003, and purchased from John Hollander on the Sinclair Lewis Fund, 2008.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Box 22: (computer disk): Restricted Fragile Material. Access copies of electronic files may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
John Hollander (1929-2013)
John Hollander, American poet and literary scholar, was born in New York City on October 28, 1929. He attended Columbia and Indiana Universities and was a Junior Fellow of the Society of Fellows of Harvard University.
Hollander was the author of more than a dozen volumes of poetry, and seven books of criticism. His many honors include the Bollingen Prize, the Levinson Prize, and the MLA Shaughnessy Medal, as well as fellowships from the Guggenheim Foundation, the MacArthur Foundation, and the National Endowment for the Arts. A Chancellor of the Academy of American Poets and poet laureate of Connecticut, he taught at Connecticut College, Hunter College, the CUNY Graduate Center, and Yale University.
Biographical note is drawn from Poets.org.
Scope and Contents
The collection consists of material created and accumulated by John Hollander in the course of his literary and teaching activities. Material includes correspondence with poets, authors, critics, academics, and composers; drafts and manuscripts of poems and essays; typescripts of writings by others and related correspondence; files relating to classes taught; music material; and other papers. The collection documents Hollander's prolific career as a poet and literary critic, as well as his relationships with other key literary figures of the late twentieth and early twenty-first century.
Arrangement
Organized into three groupings: 1966 Acquisition, May 2003 Acquisition, and January 2008 Acquisition.
Material within this collection has been organized by acquisition reflecting the fact that the collection has been acquired in increments over time.
Researchers should note that material within each acquisition overlaps with and/or relates to material found in other acquisitions. For instance, writings can be found in both groupings. In order to locate all relevant material within this collection, researchers will need to consult each acquisition described in the Collection Contents section.
Researchers should also note that similar material can be arranged differently in each acquisition, depending on how the material was organized when it was received by the library.
American literature -- 20th Century; American literature -- 21st century; American poetry -- 20th Century; American poetry -- 21st century; Literary critics, American -- 20th Century -- Archives; Poets, American -- 20th Century -- Archives; Born digital -- United States -- 21st century; Electronic documents -- United States -- 21st century; Hollander, John, 1929-2013; Yale University -- Faculty
- 1966 Acquisition, 1960-1966; 1 folder
  Scope and Contents
  Notes, drafts, and manuscripts of several poems.
  - Notes, drafts, and manuscripts of several poems., 1960-1966 (Box 1)
- May 2003 Acquisition, 2002; 0.21; (1 box)
  - Photographs from retirement party, 2002 September 20; 5 (Box 1)
- January 2008 Acquisition, 1949-2006; 18.09; (22 boxes)
  Arrangement
  Organized into three series: I. Correspondence, 1953-2006. II. Writings, 1951-2006. III. Other Material, 1949-2006.
  This acquisition includes correspondence, manuscripts and drafts of poems and essays, writings of others, teaching files, music material, and printed material.
  - Correspondence, 1953-2006; Series I
    Organized into two subseries: Alphabetical Files, and General Correspondence.
    - Alphabetical Files
      - Alvarez, A. (Alfred), 1968 December 11, undated (Box 2)
      - Agha, Shahid Ali, 1996-1998 (Box 2)
      - Amichai, Yehuda, 1973-1974 (Box 2)
      - Ammons, A. R., 1968-1993 (Box 2)
      - Anderson, Quentin, 1958-1973 (Box 2)
      - Ansen, Alan, 1958-1988 (Box 2)
      - Arendt, Hannah, 1972 (Box 2)
      - Arikha, Avigdor, 1992-2002 (Box 2)
      - Arrowsmith, William, 1976-1989 (Box 2)
      - Ashbery, John, 1961-1990 (Box 2)
      - Auden, W. H. (Wystan Hugh), 1957-1973 (Box 2)
      - Auster, Paul, 1977-1986 (Box 2)
      - Babbitt, Milton, 1982 (Box 2)
      - Barth, John, 1994-1995 (Box 2)
      - Barton, Anne, 1967-2000 (Box 2)
      - Barzun, Jacques, 1987-1994 (Box 2)
      - Beattie, Ann, no year October 31 (Box 2)
      - Bellow, Saul, 1975-1997 (Box 2)
      - Berger, Thomas, 1975-2004 (Box 2)
      - Berlin, Isaiah, 1971-1975 (Box 2)
      - Berryman, John, 1970 (Box 2)
      - Birmelin, Robert, 1988 (Box 2)
      - Bishop, Elizabeth, 1970-1977 (Box 2)
      - Blackmur, R. P. (Richard P.), 1961 (Box 2)
      - Blitzer, Charles, 1973-1985 (Box 2)
      - Bloom, Harold, 1963-1991 (Box 2)
      - Bolt, Thomas, 1988-2005 (Box 2)
      - Borroff, Marie, 1996 August 6 (Box 2)
      - Bowers, Edgar, 1988-1997 (Box 2)
      - Bradley, George, 1985-2005 (Box 2)
      - Bromwich, David, 1973-1992 (Box 2)
      - Brooks, Cleanth, 1991 August 23 (Box 2)
      - Brower, Reuben A. (Reuben Arthur), 1957-1974 (Box 2)
      - Burnett, Virgil, 1971 (Box 2)
      - Burnshaw, Stanley, 1995 October 3 (Box 2)
      - Burt, John, 1985-2004 (Box 2)
      - Calisher, Hortense, 1974-1991 (Box 2)
      - Carter, Elliott, 1986-2005 (Box 2)
      - Carver, Catherine A., 1965-1968 (Box 2)
      - Casey, John, undated (Box 2)
      - Castro, Jan Garden, 1979-1994 (Box 2)
      - Cavell, Stanley, 1975-1996 (Box 2)
      - Chomsky, Noam, no year April 28-May 19 (Box 2)
      - Cohen, Marshall, 1958-1982 (Box 2)
      - Cole, Henri, 1983-1997 (Box 2)
      - Cook, Donald, 1949-1994 (Box 2)
      - Cook, Eleanor, 1982-2004 (Box 2)
      - Cone, Edward T., 1961-1975 (Box 2)
      - Conquest, Robert, 1997-2005 (Box 2)
      - Corn, Alfred, 1974-1998 (Box 2)
      - Corso, Gregory, undated (Box 2)
      - Crase, Douglas, 1979-1985 (Box 2)
      - Crowley, John, 1991-2003 (Box 2)
      - Cunningham, J. V. (James Vincent), 1974-1977 (Box 2)
      - Danto, Arthur C., 1974 January 1 (Box 2)
      - Davie, Donald, 1960-1995 (Box 2)
      - Davies, Jordan, 1985-1988 (Box 2)
      - Davis, Lydia, 1981-1993 (Box 2)
      - Davison, Peter, 1957-1995 (Box 2)
      - De Man, Paul, 1966-1982 (Box 2)
      - DeLillo, Don, 1998-2000 (Box 2)
      - Dennett, D. C. (Daniel Clement), 1977 October 19 (Box 2)
      - Dickey, James, 1964-1973 (Box 2)
      - Disch, Thomas M., 1997 January 16 (Box 2)
      - Dixon, Stephen, 1981-1997 (Box 2)
      - Dobell, Byron, 1970-2005 (Box 2)
      - Donoghue, Denis, 1995 March 13 (Box 2)
      - Duncan, Harry, 1977-1979 (Box 2)
      - Durham, Guy, 1993 (Box 2)
      - Dworkin, Ronald, 1967-1968 (Box 2)
      - Eberhart, Richard, 1972 (Box 2)
      - Ellmann, Richard, 1968-1972 (Box 2)
      - Epstein, Barbara, 1963-1997 (Box 2)
      - Evans, Walker, 1965 April 2 (Box 2)
      - Evett, Robert, 1958-1960 (Box 2)
      - Ewart, Gavin, 1982-1983 (Box 2)
      - Feldman, Irving, 1975-2000 (Box 2)
      - Fergusson, Francis, 1956-1958 (Box 2)
      - Ferry, David, 1959-1995 (Box 2)
      - Fiedler, Leslie A., 1967-1975 (Box 2)
      - Field, Edward, 1996 (Box 2)
      - Fitzgerald, Robert, 1975-1995 (Box 2)
      - Fletcher, Angus, 1971-2004 (Box 2)
      - Ford, Harry, 1960-1999; 4 folders (Box 2)
      - Forge, Andrew, undated (Box 2)
      - Fowler, Alastair, 1990-1996 (Box 2)
      - "File stickers", undated (Box 2)
      - Frankenthaler, Helen, 1990-1991 (Box 2)
      - French, Philip, 1976-1992 (Box 2)
      - Friedman, Donald, 1950-1983 (Box 3)
      - Friedman, Sanford, 1958-1999 (Box 3)
      - Frye, Northrop, 1960-1986 (Box 3)
      - Gagnon, John H., 1963-1968 (Box 3)
      - Ginsberg, Allen, 1956-1997 (Box 3)
      - Giorcelli, Cristina, 1967-2003 (Box 3)
      - Gioia, Dana, 1982-1986 (Box 3)
      - Di Giovanni, Norman Thomas, 1968-1971 (Box 3)
      - Girodias, Maurice, 1959 September 7-29 (Box 3)
      - Godine, David R., 1972-1979 (Box 3)
      - Goehr, Alexander, 1984-1999 (Box 3)
      - Gold, Herbert, 1967 (Box 3)
      - Greenberg, Martin, 1984-2005 (Box 3)
      - Greger, Debora, 1985-1997 (Box 3)
      - Grosholz, Emily, 1981-1996 (Box 3)
      - Gross, John, 1964-1983 (Box 3)
      - Gross, Kenneth, 1982-1997 (Box 3)
      - Grossman, Allen, 1961-1982 (Box 3)
      - Gunn, Thom, 1976-1992 (Box 3)
      - Hadas, Moses, 1958 (Box 3)
      - Hadas, Rachel, 1963-2003 (Box 3)
      - Hall, Donald, 1957-2003 (Box 3)
      - Hamilton, Ian, 1972 (Box 3)
      - Hardwick, Elizabeth, undated (Box 3)
      - Harmon, William, 1978-2000 (Box 3)
      - Heaney, Seamus, 1994 March 25 (Box 3)
      - Hearne, Vicki, 1975-1993; 2 folders (Box 3)
      - Hecht, Anthony, 1966-2006 (Box 3)
      - Hellman, Lillian, 1967-1976 (Box 3)
      - Hersey, John, 1983-1984 (Box 3)
      - Hill, Geoffrey, 1979-1997 (Box 3)
      - Hine, Daryl, 1957-2000 (Box 3)
      - Hirsch, Edward, 1987-1993 (Box 3)
      - Hodgart, Matthew John Caldwell, 1974-1983 (Box 3)
      - Hoffman, Daniel, 1959-1996 (Box 3)
      - Honig, Edward, 1975-1987 (Box 3)
      - Hope, A. D. (Alec Derwent), 1965-1970 (Box 3)
      - Howard, Richard, 1963-2002 (Box 3)
      - Howe, Irving, 1959-1990 (Box 3)
      - Hunt, John Dixon, 1984-1996 (Box 3)
      - Irwin, John, 1973-2006 (Box 3)
      - Justice, Donald, 1993-2000 (Box 3)
      - Kalstone, David, 1965-1985 (Box 3)
      - Kateb, George, 1957-1988 (Box 3)
      - Keeley, Edmund, 1970-1973 (Box 3)
      - Kenedy, R.C., 1974-1976 (Box 3)
      - Kennedy, X. J., 1970-2005 (Box 3)
      - Kenner, Hugh, 1974 May 6-21 (Box 3)
      - Kenney, Richard, 1982-1990 (Box 3)
      - Kermode, Frank, 1964-1998 (Box 3)
      - Kirchwey, Karl, 1988-2004 (Box 3)
      - Kirstein, Lincoln, 1983 July 4-November 13 (Box 3)
      - Kizer, Carolyn, 1994-2003 (Box 3)
      - Klein, Ursula, 1960-1981 (Box 3)
      - Koch, Kenneth, 1961-2000 (Box 3)
      - Koethe, John, 1984-1997 (Box 3)
      - Kramer, Hilton, 1977-1984 (Box 3)
      - Kray, Elizabeth D., 1957-1978 (Box 3)
      - Kugel, James L., 1973-1988 (Box 3)
      - Lattimore, Richmond, 1980-1984 (Box 4)
      - Laughlin, James, 1972-1978 (Box 4)
      - Lehman, David, 1975-1998 (Box 4)
      - Leithauser, Brad, 1985-2005 (Box 4)
      - Lesser, Wendy, 1998-2003 (Box 4)
      - Levin, Harry, 1961-1978 (Box 4)
      - Lewis, R. W. B. (Richard Warrington Baldwin), 1968-1998 (Box 4)
      - Levin, Phillis, 1999-2003 (Box 4)
      - Linney, Romulus, 2001-2006 (Box 4)
      - Lister, Rodney, 1982-2003 (Box 4)
      - Lowell, Robert, 1964-1972 (Box 4)
      - Lucie-Smith, Edward, 1969 (Box 4)
      - Lurie, Alison, 1979 July 16-26 (Box 4)
      - Macpherson, Jay, 1966-1993 (Box 4)
      - Martin, Leslie, undated (Box 4)
      - Matthews, Harry, 1976-2002 (Box 4)
      - Matthews, William, 1967-1995 (Box 4)
      - Maxwell, William, 1980-1981 (Box 4)
      - McCarry, Charles, 1995 September 9 (Box 4)
      - McClatchy, J. D., 1976-2003 (Box 4)
      - McGann, Jerome J., 1975 February 5-May 21 (Box 4)
      - McNeil, Helen, 1965-1992 (Box 4)
      - Mendelson, Edward, 1975-1991 (Box 4)
      - Meredith, William, 1958-1978 (Box 4)
      - Merrill, James, circa 1962-1995; 7 (Box 4)
      - Merwin, W. S. (William Stanley), 1960-2003 (Box 4)
      - Mezey, Robert, 1979-2003 (Box 4)
      - Miller, Karl, 1960-2000 (Box 4)
      - Moffett, Judith, 1973-1986 (Box 4)
      - Mooney, Ted, 1982-1983 (Box 4)
      - Moritz, A. F. (Albert Frank), 1982-2003 (Box 4)
      - Moross, Jerome, 1967-1980 (Box 4)
      - Morrow, Bradford, 1996 April 27 (Box 4)
      - Moss, Howard, 1957-1985 (Box 4)
      - Murdoch, Iris, 1978-1980 (Box 4)
      - Myers, John Bernard, 1966-1977 (Box 4)
      - Nims, John Frederick, 1960-1984 (Box 4)
      - Nuland, Sherwin B., 1996-1999 (Box 4)
      - Nussbaum, Martha Craven, 1960-1979 (Box 4)
      - Oates, Joyce Carol, 1975-1983 (Box 4)
      - Orgel, Stephen, 1953-1993 (Box 4)
      - Ozick, Cynthia, 1970-2001 (Box 4)
      - Panofsky, Erwin, 1958-1961 (Box 4)
      - Parisi, Joseph, 1978-2002 (Box 4)
      - Perl, Jed, 1988-1997 (Box 4)
      - Perle, George, 1974-1981 (Box 4)
      - Perényi, Eleanor, 1974-2002 (Box 4)
      - Perutz, Kathrin, 1958-1995 (Box 4)
      - Phillips, Bob, 1981-1996 (Box 4)
      - Phillips, William and Philip Rahv, 1957-1991 (Box 4)
      - Pinsky, Robert, 1979-2000 (Box 4)
      - Plimpton, George, 2003 August 15 (Box 4)
      - Podhoretz, Norman, 1957-1999 (Box 4)
      - Poirier, Richard, 1957-2000 (Box 4)
      - Pollack, Reginald, 1962-2001 (Box 4)
      - Powers, Rick, 2000 (Box 4)
      - Price, Reynolds, 1986-1999 (Box 4)
      - Pritchard, William, 1970-2000 (Box 4)
      - Prunty, Wyatt, 1984-2005 (Box 4)
      - Quinn, Alice, 1975-2005 (Box 4)
      - Ransom, John Crowe, 1957-1972 (Box 4)
      - Rich, Adrienne, 1966-1969 (Box 4)
      - Richards, I. A. (Ivor Armstrong), 1958-1987 (Box 4)
      - Ricks, Christopher, 1988-2004 (Box 4)
      - Rorem, Ned, 1975-2004 (Box 4)
      - Roth, Philip, 1975-1998 (Box 4)
      - Rothstein, Edward, 1989 April 4 (Box 4)
      - Rudman, Mark, 1983-1989 (Box 4)
      - Salter, Mary Jo, 1993-1994 (Box 5)
      - Salzman, Eric, 1973 (Box 5)
      - Sandy, Stephen, 1970-2001 (Box 5)
      - Schapiro, Meyer, 1967-1979 (Box 5)
      - Schneewind, J. B. (Jerome B.), 1963-1981 (Box 5)
      - Schuller, Gunther, 1987-1989 (Box 5)
      - Schulman, Grace, 1978-1994 (Box 5)
      - Seth, Vikram, 1985-1986 (Box 5)
      - Shaffer, Peter, 1952-1978 (Box 5)
      - Simic, Charles, 1991 (Box 5)
      - Simmons, Charles, 1967-1986 (Box 5)
      - Simpson, Louis, 1961 (Box 5)
      - Skinner, B. F. (Burrhus Frederic), 1958-1979 (Box 5)
      - Smith, William Jay, 1988-2000 (Box 5)
      - Snow, Edward A., 1985-1988 (Box 5)
      - Solomon, Andrew, 1987-1996 (Box 5)
      - Sondheim, Stephen, 1992-1993 (Box 5)
      - Sonnenberg, Ben, 1981-2003 (Box 5)
      - Sontag, Susan, 1964-1984 (Box 5)
      - Soyer, Raphael, undated (Box 5)
      - Sparrow, John, 1968 (Box 5)
      - Spender, Stephen, 1974 (Box 5)
      - Spence, Jonathan D., 1984 (Box 5)
      - Spiegelman, Willard, 1988-2008 (Box 5)
      - Steegmuller, Francis, 1975-1983 (Box 5)
      - Steinberg, Leo, 1978-1984 (Box 5)
      - Steinberg, Saul, 1972-1994 (Box 5)
      - "Loose Tags", undated (Box 5)
      - Steiner, George, 1956-1969 (Box 5)
      - Stevens, Holly, 1964-1977 (Box 5)
      - Stone, Robert, 1999 April 2 (Box 5)
      - Strand, Mary, 1967-1993 (Box 5)
      - Strong, Roy, 1970-1974 (Box 5)
      - Styron, William, 1964-1967 (Box 5)
      - Swenson, May, 1965-2002 (Box 5)
      - Tanning, Dorothea, 1998 January 27 (Box 5)
      - Tate, Allen, 1965-1976 (Box 5)
      - Taylor, Peter, 1990 August 14 (Box 5)
      - Thwaite, Anthony, 1971-1972 (Box 5)
      - Trilling, Diana, 1963-1987 (Box 5)
      - Updike, John, 1980-1993 (Box 5)
      - Van Doren, Mark, 1947-1974 (Box 5)
      - Van Duyn, Mona, 1974-1993 (Box 5)
      - Vendler, Helen, undated (Box 5)
      - Von Hallberg, Robert, 1979-1993 (Box 5)
      - Wade, Sidney, 1990-1991 (Box 5)
      - Wain, John, 1964-1975 (Box 5)
      - Waldrop, Rosmarie, 1976-1978 (Box 5)
      - Wallace-Crabbe, Chris, 1967-1998 (Box 5)
      - Walsh, John, 1978-2006 (Box 5)
      - Walthall, Hugh, 1981-1989 (Box 5)
      - Walzer, Michael, 1993-1994 (Box 5)
      - Warren, Robert Penn, 1962-1988 (Box 5)
      - Warren, Rosanna, 1977-2004 (Box 5)
      - Weber, Katharine, 1984-1995 (Box 5)
      - Weisgall, Hugo, 1974-1975 (Box 5)
      - Weismiller, Edward Ronald, 1974-2000 (Box 5)
      - Wetzsteon, Rachel, 1993-1999 (Box 5)
      - White, Eric, 1965-1966 (Box 5)
      - Wieseltier, Leon, 1978-2000 (Box 5)
      - Wilbur, Richard, 1959-2002 (Box 5)
      - Wilkinson, Marc, 1952-1974 (Box 5)
      - Wright, Jay, 1972-2006; 2 (Box 5)
      - Yaguchi, Yorifumi, 1968-1972 (Box 5)
      - Yenser, Stephen, 1979-1997 (Box 5)
    - General Correspondence
      Arranged chronologically.
      - "General Population", 1950s-1979; 8 (Box 5)
      - "General Population", 1976-1989; 31 (Box 6)
      - "General Population", 1985-2006; 18 (Box 7)
  - Writings, 1951-2006; Series II
    Files consists of manuscripts, drafts, notes, printed material and correspondence stemming from the writing and editorial activities of John Hollander. Included are writings by Vicki Hearne and others, whose work Hollander reviewed and/or championed.
    Organized into three subseries: Writings of Others, Vicki Hearne Writings, Writings of John Hollander.
    - Writings of Others
      Arranged alphabetically by author.
      - Ashbery, John. "Houseboat Days", undated (Box 7)
      - Bloom, Harold. "Freud and the Sublime", undated (Box 7)
      - Bolt, Thomas
        - "Business and Desire", undated (Box 7)
        - "You Must Change your Life", circa 1987 (Box 7)
      - Bowers, Edgar. "For Louis Pasteur" and other manuscripts, undated (Box 7)
      - Bromwich, David. "Seperate Dwelling", undated (Box 7)
      - Corn, Alfred, undated
        - "Tongues in Trees:, undated (Box 7)
        - "The Various Light", undated (Box 7)
      - Crase, Douglas. "The Revisonist", undated (Box 7)
      - Forster, Suzie. "Connect the Dots - Seurat", 2006; 1
        Computer disk 20080102-11740.0001.
        Conditions Governing Access
        Reference copies of electronic files are available. Consult Access Services for further information.
      - Howard, Richard (translator). "The Flower of Evil" by Charles Baudelaire, undated (Box 7)
      - Kenney, Richard. "The Evolution of the Flightless Bird", undated (Box 7)
      - McClatchy, J. D. "Scenes from Another Life", undated (Box 7)
      - Merrill, James
        - "The Changing Light at Andover", undated (Box 7)
        - "The Inner Room", undated (Box 7)
        - "Santorini: Stopping the Leak", undated (Box 7)
      - Richards, _____. "Whose Endless Jar", undated (Box 7)
      - Richie, Donald. "Japan: Prose of Departure", circa 1986 (Box 7)
      - Seth, Vikram. "The Golden Gate", undated (Box 8)
      - Warren, Robert Penn
        - "Boyhood in Tabacco Country", undated (Box 8)
        - "Brother to Dragons", undated (Box 8)
        - "Have you ever Eaten Stars?", circa 1979-1980 (Box 8)
        - "Life is a Fable," 6th Revision, 1977-1980 (Box 8)
        - "Toward the Human Understanding: Poem / Poems 1986-1973" (Box 8)
        - Various manuscripts, undated (Box 8)
      - Wright, Jay
        - "Boleros", circa 1988 (Box 8)
        - "The Double Invention of Komo", undated (Box 8)
      - Unidentified
        - "Chapter 2: At the Inn", undated (Box 8)
        - "The Progress of Peace", undated (Box 8)
        - Loose typescript pages, undated; 2 (Box 8)
        - Various typescripts, 1969-1981, undated; 2 (Box 8)
        - The Other End of the Couch: Poems for Gordon Cairnie, 1964 (Box 8)
        - Reports and Speeches of the Seventh Yale Conference of the Teaching of English, 1961 April 14-15 (Box 8)
    - Vicki Hearne Writings
      - "Nervous Horses", undated; 2 (Box 8)
      - "The Horse of a Particular Time", undated (Box 8)
      - "Bellerophon and Pegasus", undated (Box 8)
      - "The Problem of Belief", circa 1982 (Box 8)
      - "Tricks of the Light", undated; 2 (Box 8)
      - Other people's writings, 2003-2005, undated; 7 (Box 8)
    - Writings of John Hollander
      - "The Question of Cupcake", 1974, undated (Box 9)
      - Cover Art Proof for "Powers of Thirteen", undated (Box 8)
      - "Hidden Rhymes", 1982 (Box 8)
      - "Behold," early drafts, undated (Box 8)
      - Various papers, 1976, undated (Box 8)
      - "Powers of Thirteen", 1982-1983, undated; 8 (Box 8)
      - "The Figure of Echo", 1981 (Box 9)
      - Prose pending, 1970-1983, undated (Box 9)
      - "On Saul Steinberg", 1951-1995 (Box 9)
      - "Stated Meeting Report", 1995 (Box 9)
      - "Review of Anthony Hecht", 1997 (Box 9)
      - "Introduction to Poirier Frost", undated (Box 9)
      - Draft for Daryl Hine essay, undated (Box 9)
      - Marianne Moore, undated (Box 9)
      - "Melodious Guile", undated (Box 9)
      - "The Work of Poetry", undated (Box 9)
      - "Of Mopsa the Fairy", undated (Box 9)
      - Various manuscripts, 1984-1998, undated; 2 (Box 9)
      - "Primer of Medieval Latin", 1976-1977 (Box 9)
      - Various materials, 2005-2006 (Box 9)
      - Notebooks, 1976-2006; 5 (Box 9)
      - Notebooks, 1972-; 4 (Box 10)
      - "Never reprinted or published", 1959-1987 (Box 10)
      - Various manuscripts, 1997-2006, undated; 2 (Box 10)
      - "Rhyme's Reason", 1981-1989; 3 (Box 10)
      - "Harp Lake", 1988 (Box 10)
      - "Harp Lake", 1988; 8 (Box 11)
      - "Spectral Emanations", 1978 (Box 11)
      - "Movie-Going", 1962; 2 (Box 11)
      - "The Night Mirror", 1971; 2 (Box 11)
      - "Selected Poems", 1972 (Box 11)
      - "Reflections on Espionage", 1976 (Box 11)
      - "Images of Voice", 1968 (Box 11)
      - "Blue Wine and Other Poems", 1979 (Box 11)
      - "Vision and Resonance", 1975 (Box 11)
      - "In the Time and Place 2", 1985, undated (Box 11)
      - "Harp Lake", 1967-1998; 9 (Box 11)
      - "Tesserae", 1983-1993; 8 (Box 11)
      - "Figurehead", 1986-1999; 5 (Box 11)
      - "Juvenilia", 1945-1958; 2 (Box 11)
      - "A Cracklin of Thorns", 1951-1986 (Box 12)
      - "Movie-Going", 1957-1965; 2 (Box 12)
      - "Visions from the Ramble", 1964-1965 (Box 12)
      - "Types of Shape", 1957-1990; 3 (Box 12)
      - "Town and Country Matters", 1959-2006; 3 (Box 12)
      - "Night Mirror", 1964-1972; 3 (Box 12)
      - "Head of the Bed", undated (Box 12)
      - "Powers of Thirteen", 1983 (Box 12)
      - "Spectral Emanations", 1974-1989; 3 (Box 12)
      - "Some Fugitives Take Cover", 1963-1986 (Box 12)
      - "Melodious Guile", undated (Box 12)
      - "Necessary Hieroglyphs", undated (Box 12)
      - "Breaking into Song", undated (Box 12)
      - "Poems that Talk to Themselves", undated (Box 12)
      - "Figure of Echo", undated; 2 (Box 12)
      - "Spenser's Undersong", undated (Box 12)
      - "Observation on Moore's Syllables Schemes", undated (Box 12)
      - "O Heavy Verse!", undated (Box 12)
      - "The Poetry of Nonesense", undated (Box 12)
      - "Far Space and Long Antiquity", undated (Box 12)
      - "The Work of Poetry", 1987-1996 (Box 12)
      - "The Work of Poetry", 1987-1996; 5 (Box 13)
      - "Melodious Guile", 1988; 4 (Box 13)
      - "Poetry: Reflections on Espionage", 1974 (Box 13)
      - "The Figure of Echo", undated (Box 13)
      - "Powers of Thirteen", 1983 (Box 13)
      - "Spectral Emanations", 1978; 3 (Box 13)
      - "Selected Poetry", 1993; 3 (Box 13)
      - "Harp Lake", 1988 (Box 14)
      - "Tesserae", 1993 (Box 14)
      - Various manuscripts, 1956-2005; 4 (Box 14)
      - "Tales Told of the Fathers", 1975 (Box 14)
        Related Archival Materials note
        See also: Oversize, Box 21
      - "Picture Window", 1995-2003; 12 (Box 14)
      - Articles and reviews, 1956-1978; 4 (Box 14)
      - Various manuscripts, 1955-2001; 8 (Box 15)
      - Printed clippings, 1959-1997 (Box 15)
      - "Steinberg- and RE: others", 1972-1978 (Box 15)
      - "The Naming and Blaming of Cats", 1989-1995 (Box 15)
      - Printed clippings and pamphlets, 1956-2001 (Box 15)
      - "Larry Day", undated (Box 15)
      - "Robert Frost and the Renewal of Birds", undated (Box 15)
      - Various manuscripts, 1956-2003; 6 (Box 15)
      - "Loc. Am", undated (Box 15)
      - "Reflections on Espionage", 1974-1999; 4 (Box 15)
      - "Blue Wine", 1975-1985; 3 (Box 16)
      - "Tales Told of the Fathers", 1971-1975; 2 (Box 16)
      - "Powers of Thirteen", 1981-1982; 2 (Box 16)